字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously, on "The Flash"...
四年后
Four years from now,
布兰德博士发明了一种技术
Dr. Brand invents the technology
可以把萨维塔困在神速力中
that traps Savitar in the Speed Force.
这是神速力火箭筒
This is the Speed Force bazooka.
它可以困住萨维塔吗
And that's gonna trap Savitar?
我知道你现在是什么
I know what you are.
你是时间残余
You're a time remnant.
因为我不是真正的
You all shunned me
巴里·艾伦你们都躲着我
because I wasn't the true Barry Allen.
我只是个时间偏差
I was an aberration.
你怎么会变成萨维塔呢
How did you become Savitar?
我很病态  很孤独  上帝不会有痛苦
I was broken and alone. God feels no pain.
我要做的就是成为上帝
All I had to do was become one.
爱瑞丝·韦斯特死前二十四小时
来自费利西蒂·斯莫克的信息
主题：能量源
我没有找到能用的
爱瑞丝
Iris.
你知道我现在想要什么吗
You know what I'd love right now?
你想要什么都行
Anything you want.
鱼子酱
Caviar.
Caviar?
好吧  不过有点晚了
Okay. Well, it's just a little late,
可能找不到还在卖鱼子酱的店了
so it might be hard for me to find a place that's open that has it.
不过我会有办法的
But I'll find an assortment.
谢谢
Thank you.
陪着我  好吗
Just stay with me, okay?
整个小队都在想办法
The whole team's working on this.
我们能在二十四小时内完成很多事
And we can accomplish a lot in 24 hours.
我知道
I know we can.
我没事  巴里  真的
I'm fine, Barry. Really.
买鱼子酱
Get some caviar...
巴里
Hi, Barry.
我有些话想对你说
there's something that I need to say to you.
闪电侠
第三季
第二十二集
西斯科
Hey, Cisco.
什么
What?
在哪
Where?
好的  我去接你
All right, I'll come pick you up.
什么事
What is it?
非常好的消息
Really good news.
超能力联合调查组
莱拉
Lyla.
二位
Gentlemen.
-有点冷啊  -是啊
- It's a wee bit chilly. - Yeah.
能进去谈吗
Wanna take this inside?
那座楼里每个角落都被监听了
Every square inch of that building is bugged.
我想还是在外面谈比较好
Figured it was better to talk out here.
好的  是的  我喜欢吹风
Okay. Yeah, I love the breeze.
-是的  -尤其是这种天气
- Yeah. - On days like this.
没错
Yeah.
我收到了你们的信息
So, I got your message.
但你们得再说一遍你们到底要什么
But, you're gonna have to run me through exactly what you need again.
-好的  -我们在造一口炮
- Yeah... - So, we're building a cannon.
-是的  -火箭筒  之类的
- Right. - Bazooka... thing.
-就像是一种陷阱  -为了启动它
- It's a sort of trap. - In order to turn it on,
我们需要给它功能  得用非常强大
we need something to power it. Something extremely powerful
-且可再生的能量  -好的
- and regenerative. - Okay.
所以  我就调动了我们的卫星
Yeah, so, I tasked our satellite to look for
寻找符合我们能量要求的设备
anything that might have our specific power requirements,
你绝对想不到  我们找到了
and--wouldn't you know it-- we found something that has
完全符合要求的东西  而且就在
exactly what we need. And it's right there
那座大楼里  难以置信吧
in that building. Crazy?
我觉得你不应该窥探我  西斯科
I really don't think you should be spying on me, Cisco.
我们都是朋友了  这算窥探吗
Is it spying if we're friends?
但他说得对  是吧  你们真的有
But he's right, isn't he? You have something, don't you?
那是一项支配者发明的技术
It's a piece of the Dominators' technology.
我们从坠毁在中城的飞船上发现的
We got it from the ship that crashed in Central City.
-太好了  -不能给你们  巴里
- That's great. - You can't have it, Barry.
-什么  -莱拉
- What? - Lyla...
我们找遍了所有地方
We've searched everywhere.
这是我们唯一可用的技术
This tech is the only thing that we can use.
我不能那么做
I can't do it.
是因为小莎拉吗
Is this because of Baby Sara?
听我说  我承认我也考虑过
Look... I'll admit, it's been hard not to wonder
有女儿而不是儿子会是什么样
what it would have been like to have a daughter instead of a son,
但我在意的是事发原因而非发生了什么
but this is less about what happened than why it happened.
我犯了个大错
I made a big mistake.
这正是我所担心的
Exactly my concern.
巴里  很多人不惜发动战争来争夺这种技术
Barry, this is the kind of tech that wars are fought over.
如果发生了意外  落入了坏人手里
If something happens and it gets into the wrong hands,
数百万人会死去
people could die. Millions.
说实话  我不知道能否放心把它交给你
And frankly, I don't know if I can trust you to have it.
麦考斯指挥官
Director Michaels.
我得走了
I gotta go.
莱拉  如果我们不用这个
Lyla, if we don't use this,
爱瑞丝会死的
Iris is going to die.
就在今晚
Tonight.
对不起  巴里  这次我帮不了你
I'm sorry, Barry. I can't help you this time.
你得想另一个办法
You'll have to find another way.
-你说真的吗  -真的
- Are you serious? - Yeah.
如果莱拉不把支配者的科技给我们
Yeah, if Lyla won't let us have the Dominators' tech,
那我们要闯进天眼会
then we are gonna break into ARGUS,
把它偷走
and we're gonna steal it.
我和沃利会穿墙进去
Wally and I will phase through the walls.
我们会神不知鬼不觉
We'll be in and out of there before
进去然后出来
anyone even gets off a shot.
这是不可能的
Uh, hello? No, you won't.
-我们...  -那是什么
- Yeah, we-- - What is that?
那是超能力者的超能力抑制器
That is a meta-human power dampener.
整栋楼到处都是
And it's all over the building,
所以你不能在里面使用超能力
so you can't use your powers inside.
我们能用别的东西发动神速力枪吗
Can we use anything else to power this Speed Force gun?
神速力火箭筒
Speed Force bazooka.
-火箭筒  -别无他法
- Bazooka. - Nothing else.
控制异次元能量需要
Manipulating extra-dimensional energy requires,
巨大到荒谬的能量
well, a ridiculous lot of energy,
只有支配者的科技才能做到
and the Dominator tech's the only thing that can do that.
我有...  我有个办法  大伙
Hey, I have-- I have an idea, gang.
如果我们把你和爱瑞丝送上去巴黎的飞机
What if we just put you-- put Iris on a plane to Paris,
-或更远的地方呢  -不行
- or somewhere far away? - No.
地球任何角落  萨维塔都能找到她
There's nowhere on Earth that Savitar wouldn't find her.
各位  窃取支配者的科技
Guys. Stealing this Dominators' tech
是我们唯一的选择
is our only option, all right?
巴里  天眼会比五角大楼还森严
Barry. ARGUS is more secure than the pentagon.
如果你在里面不能使用超能力
If your powers don't work in there,
-你要怎么通过安检  -好吧
- how are you gonna get past security? - Okay.
我们现在要对付的是  监控摄像头
This is what we're dealing with: surveillance cameras.
我退出
I'm out.
-眼球扫描  -不行
- Eye scans. - No.
掌纹
Palm prints.
热量传感器
Heat sensors.
-什么  -激光传感器
- What? - Laser sensors.
他们还真是全方位都考虑到了
They really thought of everything, didn't they?
这还只是一楼
That's just the first floor.
你是说这是防御建筑历史上
So, you're saying this is the most fortified structure
防御最强的建筑
in the history of fortified structures,
他们不能使用超能力
they can't use their superpowers,
而我们只有不到十四个小时
and we have less than 14 hours
去偷这个东西
to steal the thing.
而我们当中没人是偷盗大师
And none of us are master thieves.
对  我们都不是
No. No, we're not.
西伯利亚
1892年
你好啊  闪电侠
Hello, Flash.
我需要你的帮忙
I need your help.
巴里·艾伦  中城英雄
Barry Allen. The hero of Central City.
这里是1892年的西伯利亚
This is Siberia in the year 1892.
有些超出了你的管辖范围了
We're a little out of your jurisdiction.
听我说完  我要招募你
Yeah, hear me out. I wanna recruit you,
参加一项任务
for a mission.
我已经在帮助一群傻子行善者了
I'm already helping a bunch of idiot do-gooders.
抱歉  我受够了团队合作
Sorry. I'm up to my fuzzy hood in teamwork.
如果我说请  你会帮我吗
Would it help if I said please?
不会  你身边已经有一群超级英雄了
No. And you already have a bunch of superhero types in your life.
为什么来找我
Why ask me?
你有一套
Well, you have a...
特殊的技能
particular set of skills.
说得真好听
Great movie.
上次我们试着成为好兄弟
Last time we tried to be buddy-buddy,
结果并不理想
it didn't work out so well...
对你而言
for you.
现在为什么相信我
Why trust me now?
老实说吧  否则我就登上那艘飞船
Spit it out, or I'm gonna step onto that ship
假装我俩从没见过
and pretend like this conversation never happened.
爱瑞丝
Iris.
-你的女朋友  -未婚妻
- Oy. The girlfriend. - Fiancée.
恭喜你  她怎么了
Mazel tov. What about her?
如果你不帮我  她就会死
If you don't help me, she's gonna die.
真爱  那是你的论调
True love. That's your pitch.
那是我仅有的
It's all I've got.
我猜拯救你的女朋友
And I assume saving your girlfriend
需要我们做一些不合法的事
requires us doing something less than lawful?
我们要闯进天眼会  偷取外星人的能量源
We need to break into ARGUS and steal an alien power source.
闪电侠当小偷吗
The Flash, a thief?
这才是适合我的任务  一个条件
That's my kind of mission. One condition:
按我的规则来
my rules.
按你的规则来
Your rules.
我知道我们还没有飞机
No, I know we don't have a plane.
我们偷一架  如何  我们会还回去的
We steal a plane, okay? We'll put it back. All right?
我们从飞机上跳伞  然后落在屋顶上
And we parachute out of the plane, and land on the roof--
要落在正确的屋顶上  对吧  然后...
gotta land on the right roof, all right? And then...
从通气管道下去
right down the air ducts.
《不大可能完成的任务》风格
Mission Improbable style.
-简单  -简单
- Easy. - Easy?
-没错  -那反恐导弹呢
- Yes. - What about the counterterrorism missiles?
-什么  -没错
- What? - Yeah.
你们好  乔  西斯科
Hello, Joe! Cisco.
爱瑞丝  钻戒不错  闪闪的
Iris! Love the ice. Sparkly.
寒冷队长
Captain Cold.
史纳特  你在这里做什么
Snart, what the hell are you doing here?
史纳特会帮助我闯入天眼会
Snart's gonna help me break into ARGUS--
拿到能量源
get the power source.
尴尬
Awkward.
我看得出来你们有很多话要讲
I can see you all have a lot to talk about.
我会去实验室里  准备好一切
I'll be down in your lab, getting everything ready.
巴里  你是疯了吗
Barry, are you out of your mind?
我还以为他跟传奇们一起
I thought he was with the Legends.
-是的  -不  他死了
- He is. - No, he dead.
-这个  -你又穿越时间了
- Well... - You time travelled again?
-是的  -最初因为这个
- Yeah. - That's what got us
才落到今天这田地
in this mess in the first place.
我记得你不是说再也不那么做了吗
I thought you said you would never do that again.
我还说了会不惜一切来拯救你
I also said I would do whatever it takes to save you.
这个可没变
That hasn't changed.
我肯定你们也会有同样的感觉  对吧
And I'm pretty sure you all feel the same way, too. Right?
我没有改变时间
Look, I'm not changing time.
等任务完成
I will put him back,
我回把他送回找到他的地方
right where I found him. After we get what we need.
行  你说需要史纳特帮助  我们就需要他
Fine. You say we need Snart's help, we need his help.
那计划是什么
So what's the plan?
你在做什么
What are you doing?
闪电侠
Flash...
在战斗中弄坏了我的战衣
damaged my suit in our fight.
样子真酷  很有神格
Pretty badass. Very godlike.
心仪工作的制服
Well, dress for the job you want.
我们是一个队伍吧
We're a team, right?
巴里和凯瑟琳  再次联手
Barry and Caitlin, at it again.
你不是凯瑟琳
You're not Caitlin.
我也不是巴里
And I'm not Barry.
你确定真的要经历这事吗
You sure you're gonna go through with this?
-什么  -杀死爱瑞丝
- What? - Killing Iris.
你要带她去因凡蒂诺街
You're gonna take her to Infantino Street,
然后用一把金属长矛刺穿她后背
and ram a metal spear through her back?
不是她就是我
Well, it's either her or me.
如果她不死  我就不会诞生
If she doesn't die, I'm never born.
没错  但是...
Right, but...
在这张漂亮的小脸蛋后边
behind that pretty little face of yours,
你依然记得巴里所做的一切
you still remember everything that Barry does.
所以你记得和爱瑞丝一起长大
So you remember growing up with Iris,
与她坠入爱河  亲吻她
falling in love with her, kissing her.
你确定你准备好了结她了吗
You sure you're ready to end her life?
我所记得的
What I remember...
是被当作可有可无的生命创造出来
is being created as a disposable life.
命中注定在巴里·艾伦
Something to be... thrown away
用完之后就要被抛弃的
when Barry Allen was done with me.
他不关心我
He didn't care about me.
我为什么要关心他的爱人
Why should I care about his love?
你不是改变想法了吧
You're not having second thoughts, are you?
很好  因为你知道你需要做什么
Good. Because you know what you need to do,
当时机到来时  我希望你能准备好
and when the time comes, I expect you to be ready.
怎么了
What is it?
巴里穿越回去找史纳特帮他
Barry went back in time to get Snart's help
从天眼会偷取能量源
with stealing the power source from ARGUS.
能量源  做什么
Power source? For what?
无关紧要了
Oh... it doesn't matter.
需要我阻止他吗
Well, should I stop them?
不用  让他们去拿
No. Let them take it.
没有什么神速力枪能阻止神
No speed gun can stop a god.
我猜能量源很有可能在这里
My guess is the power source is most likely here.
-为什么是那里  -因为那是设施
- Why there? - Because it's the deepest part
最深的地方  如果它真如你所说那么珍贵
of the facility, and if it's as valuable as you say it is,
那么一个设施的最深处
then the deepest recesses of any facility
通常是最安全的地方
are usually the most secure.
聪明  史纳特  "聪明  史纳特"
Smart, Snart. "Smart, Snart."
我去继续入侵  来确定位置
I'm gonna keep hackin' away and find out for sure.
你知道还有什么可能在下边吗
Do you have any idea what else might be down there?
不重要  你只需记住四条规则
Don't matter. There are only four rules you need to remember.
制定计划  实施计划
Make the plan, execute the plan,
料到计划会出岔子
expect the plan to go off the rails...
抛弃计划
throw away the plan.
听我指示  你不会有事的
Follow my lead and you'll be fine.
我相信你
I'm trusting you.
我们都相信你
We all are.
只是别在婚宴上把我安排到单身座位
Just don't sit me at the single's table at the wedding reception.
只是好奇一问  你们计划好怎么进去了吗
Just out of curiosity, you have a plan for getting in there?
我都计划好了
I've got that covered.
给  稍等  对  好
Oh, ah--here, hold that for a second. Yeah, okay,
好  别看
and--kay-- and don't look.
闪电侠  超级英雄
Hey, Flash. Superhero.
拜托戴上面具  这里有个平民呢
Cowl on, please? We got civilians in the house.
没事  HR  我们敢把性命
It's okay. H.R., we're trusting Tracy
交到特蕾西手上  这事也能相信她
with our lives. We can trust her with this.
说得对  好  我把手拿下来了
Good point. Yeah. Okay, I'll put my hands down now.
好
Okay.
早该想到了的
Totally should've figured that out.
-继续  -好
- Well, carry on. - All right.
好  乔  我要你把爱瑞丝
All right, Joe. I need you to take Iris
带到离这里  离我遥远的地方
some place far away from here. Far away from me.
-巴里  -我不能知道地点
- Barry. - I can't know where.
如果我知道了  萨维塔也就知道了
If I know, then Savitar knows.
我带上沃利
I'll get Wally.
我们会保护好她  别担心
We'll keep her safe, don't worry.
这一刻终于来了
So here we are.
这不是告别
This is not good-bye.
对
Yeah.
听着
Look...
我知道你会不惜一切拯救我
I know you're gonna do whatever it takes to save me,
但同时不要丢失了自我  好吗
but don't lose yourself in the process, okay?
你们好
Hello.
哈里
Harry.
闪电小子  乔
Kid, Joe.
爱瑞丝
Iris.
你们怎么到这段多元宇宙来了
What brings you folk to this section of the multiverse?
那是什么
What's that?
提醒我们还剩多少时间
It's how much time we have left.
-在什么之前  -在我们失败之前
- Before what? - Before we lose.
我们在准备去旧金山的直升飞机
We're prepping the chopper for San Francisco now.
收到  长官
Copy that, sir...
麦考斯指挥官  你不是要去旧金山吗
Director Michaels. I thought you were en route to San Francisco.
计划有变  我收到闪电侠的意外礼物
Plans changed. I received an unexpected gift from the Flash.
寒冷队长
Captain Cold?
见到粉丝总是很高兴
Always nice to meet a fan.
我要把犯人带去关起来
I'm taking the prisoner to lock-up.
没问题  请出示身份证件
Of course. We'll just need your ID.
数据库查询
莱拉
麦克斯
指挥官
等待扫描
花了好多时间做天眼会的假证件
Spent so much time on that ARGUS fake ID.
那玩意简直是杰作
That thing's a masterpiece.
眼球扫描
Your eye scan?
扫描中....
莱拉
麦考斯
指挥官
扫描结束
身份确认
你们可真是小心谨慎啊
You boys really dot the "I"s and cross the "T"s.
最后  麦考斯指挥官
And finally, Director Michaels:
猫王  香蕉
Elvis, banana.
-搞什么  -难到我了
- What the hell? - Search me.
猫王  香蕉  是词汇联想游戏
Elvis, banana-- it's word association.
巴里得按顺序答出
Barry must have to come up with the next correct words
-后面的词汇  -比如"花生酱  培根"
- in the sequence. - Like "Peanut butter, bacon."
-对  凯文·贝肯  -柔和  橙黄
- Yeah, Kevin Bacon. - Mellow, yellow.
-詹姆斯·布朗  劈叉  -好了
- James Brown, split. - Okay.
巴里  你得拖住他们
Barry, you're gonna have to stall.
我重复  长官  猫王  香蕉
I repeat, ma'am. Elvis, banana.
天啊  你还年轻就这么暴力了
My, my, my. Getting rather violent in your young age.
对  你年轻时在干什么
Yeah, what were you doing?
魔术
Magic.
-厉害把戏  -你也是厉害把戏
- Neat trick. - Was a neat trick, yourself.
HR地球上的转换器
Transmogrifier from H.R.'s Earth.
给你
Here you go.
西斯科  接着去哪
Cisco, where to next?
好  你们去搭...
Okay, you will take the...
东边的电梯
east elevator?
他们该搭西边的电梯
They should do the west elevator.
-我同意特蕾西  -巴里  去搭西边的电梯
- I agree with Tracy. - Barry, take the west elevator.
我小时候常看到你做这个
I used to watch you do that as a kid.
我觉得你太酷了
I thought you were so cool.
我怎么跟你说的  枪不酷
What'd I tell you? Guns aren't cool,
-只是用来保护他人  -对
- they're just for protection. - Right.
爸  听着  我知道大家都很难受
Dad, look, I know this is hard for everyone,
但我感觉你最难受
but I feel like it's hardest for you.
爸  我能告诉你件事吗
Dad, can I tell you something?
说吧
Yep.
我十六岁的时候
When I was 16, um...
我和巴里互换了房间  好让我在宵禁后
Barry and I switched rooms, so that I could sneak out
从窗户偷溜出去
of the window past curfew.
-真的  -等等
- It's true. - Wait a minute.
你
You-- --
你跟我说那是因为
you told me that it was because
巴里不喜欢街道上
Barry didn't like the noise
-发出的噪音  -对  才不是
- from the street. - Yeah, no.
这不赖我  我的宵禁是晚上八点
But in my defense, my curfew was 8:00 P.M.
-是啊  有点严  -有点吗
- Yeah, I was a little strict. - A little?
好吧  既然我们都在坦白了
Okay, since-- since we're confessing,
记得我跟你们说
remember, um, when I told you guys
我们有一个月不能出去吃
that we couldn't eat out for a month,
因为我在给你和巴里存
because I was saving money for yours and Barry's
-大学学费  -记得
- college tuition? - Yeah.
我拿了其中一些去参加蓝调巡游
I took some of that money, and I went on a blues cruise.
沃克小子在演出  只去了三天
Junior Walker was playing. It was just for three days.
爸
Dad.
这让我想起了  那首
Oh, that reminds me. What, um...
那首你经常唱的歌叫什么
What was that song you used to sing all the time?
不记得了
You don't remember?
I don't remember.
-《如何俘获芳心》  -《如何俘获芳心》
- "What Does It Take." - "What Does It Take"!
*我努力了  努力了*
*I tried, I tried*
*想尽一切办法*
*In every way I could*
*让你看到我有多爱你*
*To make you see how much I love you*
*希望你能明白*
*I hope you understood*
-我爱你  -我也爱你  爸爸
- I love you. - I love you too, Dad.
帮我拿着这个  拜托了
Take this for me, please.
以防万一
Just in case.
一定要交还给巴里
Make sure you give it back to Barry.
好
Okay.
古鲁德
-谁是古鲁德  -能心电感应的大猩猩
- Who's Grodd? - Telepathic gorilla.
在另一个地球上饶了他一命
Spared his life on another Earth,
他却来入侵中城
so he could invade Central City.
这就是仁慈的下场
That's what mercy gets you.
猎豹女
丘比特
沃勒肯定就在这关押她的自杀小队
This must be where Waller kept her suicide squad.
我想就是这个了  来吧
I think this is it. Come on.
西斯科  我们找到了
Cisco, we found it.
西斯科
Cisco?
[超能力联合调查组]
-西斯科  能听见我吗  -清清楚楚
- Hey, Cisco, can you read me? - Loud and clear.
好  我们找到了
Hey. Uh, so, we found it.
干得漂亮
Jackpot!
但走廊尽头好像有什么信号干扰
But there seems to be some kind of signal interference
牢房在蒙哥马利三千里面
at the end of the hall, and the lock is the Montgomery 3000.
蒙哥马利三千
The Montgomery 3000.
等等  很糟糕吗
Wait, is that bad?
我们遇到的是25吨重的大门
Well, we're looking at a 25-ton door
能经受住三千万吨核爆炸
that can withstand a 30-megaton nuclear blast.
更别说这完全是防炸弹的
And aside from being completely bombproof,
蒙哥马利三千只能由
the Montgomery 3000 can only be unlocked
三个不同的人用三个密码
by a voice-recognition system necessitating
通过语音识别系统打开
three different passcodes from three different people,
如果那样还不够
and as if that weren't already enough,
这玩意造价为一千万
the thing costs $10 million to build.
37秒
37 seconds.
我肯定是疏于练习了
I must be out of practice.
天眼会该把钱要回来了
Well, ARGUS should ask for their money back.
等等
Wait!
制定计划  实施计划
Make the plan, execute the plan.
料到计划会出岔子
Expect the plan to go off the rails.
我也算见过世面的
Seen a lot of things,
但一半是人  一半是鲨鱼
but a half-man, half-shark
还真是头一回见
takes the cake.
难以置信天眼会把鲨鱼王变成了看门狗
I can't believe ARGUS turned King Shark into a guard dog.
鲨鱼王  真可爱
King Shark. That's adorable.
给我冷冻枪
Give me your cold gun.
你想用来干嘛  说清楚
So you can do what, exactly?
史纳特  要偷走那技术只有一个办法
Snart, there's only one way that tech's getting out of here.
我明白了
Oh, I see.
你把我招进来
You didn't just recruit me
不只是因为我的偷盗技能吧
for my skills as a thief, did you?
你想要的是一个
You wanted a partner who wouldn't mind
不在意你杀戮的伙伴
if you got all murder-y.
我跟你说了我要对付什么
I told you what I'm up against.
行了吗
All right?
给我枪
Give me the gun.
打开门
Open the door.
Open the door!
你看过《孤岛鲨魂》吗  巴里
Have you seen "Shark Week," Barry?
我可是怎么看都不厌呢
Me, I can't get enough of it.
还好乘波号上有电视
Good thing the Waverider has cable.
你想说什么
What's your point?
鲨鱼大多是冷血动物
Most sharks are cold-blooded,
可大白鲨跟我们这位朋友一样
but the great white shark, like our friend in there,
部分算是温血动物
is partially warm-blooded.
他对低温特别敏感
He's susceptible to cold.
从不待在低于12摄氏度的水中
Never strays into water colder than 53.6 degrees Fahrenheit.
如果我们能把房间的温度调到12度以下
If we lower the temperature in that room to 53.5 degrees,
鲨鱼王就会睡过去
King Shark should fall asleep
跟个小宝宝一样
like a little baby.
当然  你也可以过去杀了他
Or, you can go ahead and kill him,
证明你有多厉害  你选吧
and prove what a badass you are. Your choice.
抛弃计划
Throw away the plan.
特蕾西·布兰德
Tracy Brand, you know,
这种时刻就能提醒我
it's moments like this I'm reminded that S.T.A.R. Labs
尖端科研实验室不只是聪明人的天堂
is so much more than a haven for beautiful minds, it's--
-是微型吉特斯  -真不错
- It's a miniature Jitters. - Isn't it--ohh, wow. Mmm!
覆盆子和香菜
Raspberry and coriander.
-是  就像家一样  -是啊
- Yes it is--it's a home... - Yeah.
这就是家  就是我的家
is what it is. You know what? It's my home.
有我的家人
It's my... it's my family.
尽管  我
Although, I--
你知道吗  我想说
you know what, I will say...
我得告诉你
I have to tell you,
-我并不是时时都有归属感  -什么
- I haven't always felt I belong completely. - What?
缺少一种明确的使命感
Yeah, lacking a clear sense of purpose sometimes.
然后你来了
But then you arrived.
我来了吗  对  是的
I did? Oh, yeah, I did.
没错  你来了  你在这
Oh, yeah, you did. Here you are. Yeah.
有你和我一起
And with you here,
我明白了我的使命
I understand my purpose.
那就是我们
It's us.
你我进行的思维碰撞  很强大
You and me. That meeting of the mind that we have, it's just so powerful--
可HR  你来自另一个地球
But H.R., you're from another Earth--
-是  -我没工作
-Yeah, I--yeah-- - I'm a unemployed,
过去是个研究生
former grad student, who--
来尖端实验室和我一起工作吧
Come work at S.T.A.R. Labs with me.
可以吗  虽然没多少工资
Okay? I mean, it doesn't pay much.
-有多少  -几乎没有
- How much? - Ah, it pays next to nothing.
可你知道吗  这不重要
But you know what? It wouldn't matter.
我们可以一起  想象一下  我启发你
We'd be together. Imagine: me inspiring you,
然后你运用那份启发
and you applying that inspiration,
我们就可以一起改变世界
and us changing the world together.
还可以喝超多咖啡
And drinking so much coffee!
特蕾西·布兰德
Tracy Brand.
你能给我这个荣幸
Will you do me the honor
加入闪电侠队吗
of joining Team Flash?
和你一起  当然原意
With you? I'd love to.
无论如何  你先请
By all means, you first.
谢了
Thanks.
让我想起了《大白鲨》
Reminds me of "Jaws."
他们没展示鲨鱼  因为没钱做出
They didn't show the shark because they couldn't afford
好的特效场面
to make it look good.
你觉得他会睡多久
How long do you think he'll stay asleep?
我喜欢《孤岛鲨魂》  但我不是海洋生物学家
I like "Shark Week." I'm not a marine biologist.
史纳特
Snart!
巴里
Barry!
两分钟后这里
This place is gonna be crawling
就全是天眼会的特工
with ARGUS agents in the next two minutes.
往好处想  巴里
Look on the bright side, Barry.
你可以借此显示你冷酷的本来面目
This is your chance to show how ruthless you really are.
有时必须做出艰难的决定  巴里
Sometimes you gotta make a tough call, Barry.
西斯科
Cisco?
我们需要帮助
We need your help.
我拿到了能量源  可史纳特被困在牢里
I have the energy source, but Snart's trapped inside
与鲨鱼王一起  你得把门打开
the cell with King Shark. You gotta open the door.
我黑不进主机
I can't hack into the mainframe.
快点  行吗
Hurry, all right?
西斯科在想办法
Cisco's working on it.
无论如何都不要回头看
Whatever you do, don't look behind you.
如果西斯科救了我  告诉他我会...
If Cisco saves my life, tell him I'll...
在我妹妹面前为他说好话
put in a good word with my sister.
拜托了...
Come on...
快出来  快出来
Come on, come on!
快  快  快  快
Come on, come on, come on, come on!
-我抓住你了  -巴里
- I got you! - Barry!
我抓住你了  我抓住你了
I got you, I got you!
-巴里  -我抓住你了
- Barry! - I got you!
坚持住
Hang on!
快  西斯科  马上关门
Now, Cisco, now! Close it!
见识过了
Been there.
闪电侠
Flash!
我们出去吧
Let's get out of here.
莱拉
Lyla.
巴里
Barry.
我说过我不能把这个给你
I told you I couldn't give this to you.
-是的  -你还偷偷溜进来
- Yeah. - And you snuck in here anyway?
只要能救爱瑞丝  莱拉  我会不顾一切
To save Iris' life, Lyla. Yeah. I'll do anything.
也不是一切
Not anything.
我在监控录像上看到了整个过程
I saw the whole thing on the security monitors.
你本可以放任史纳特去死
You could have left Snart to die.
你却不顾自己会被抓和爱瑞丝会死去救他
But you risked your freedom and Iris' life to save him.
你就这样把它给我了吗
You're just gonna let me have it?
既然知道这个可以救爱瑞丝
I couldn't let Iris die knowing that
我不能置之不顾
that could save her.
我知道如果约翰也命悬一线
And I know you'd do the same thing for me
你也会为我做同样的事情
if it were John's life on the line.
谢谢
Thank you.
快去吧
Now go.
救爱瑞丝
Do it.
再把这家伙带回他的时间线去
And get this guy back to wherever he belongs.
抢了我的台词
Took the words right out of my mouth.
告诉我  史纳特
Tell me, Snart,
你刚才觉得我有那个念头吗
did you think I had it in me?
不管你
To leave you behind?
我不确定
I wasn't sure.
我一直相信你有潜力
Always known you had the potential to be
能像他们一样无情
as ruthless as they come.
你的过去造就了一切  跟我一样
Your history made sure of that, same as mine.
谁知道呢  也许我们因此才合得来
Who knows, maybe that's why we get along.
你看得见我心中的善  我看得见你心中的恶
You see the good in me. I see the bad in you.
-也许吧  -给个建议
- Maybe. - Piece of advice:
别再试图用萨维塔的计谋打败他
stop trying to beat Savitar at his own game.
你的善就是你的优势
Your goodness is your strength.
也许是我太多愁善感了
And call me sentimental--
我觉得闪电侠应该继续做个英雄
I think the Flash should remain a hero.
好好照顾自己  史纳特
Take care of yourself, Snart.
别牵挂我
No strings on me.
No strings on me...
我们办到了  我们弄到了支配者的技术
We did it! We got the Dominator tech.
太好了  太好了
Yes, yes!
-爱瑞丝在哪  -爱瑞丝...
- Where's Iris? - Ah, Iris--
和老哈里·威尔斯一起安全地躲在地球二
safely stashed away on Earth-2 with Ole Harry Wells.
不
No.
巴里  萨维塔知道爱瑞丝在哪儿了
Barry! Savitar knows where Iris is.
萨维塔要来了
Savitar's coming.
-什么  -快  乔
- What? - Now. Joe.
-爱瑞丝  躲在我身后  -爸
- Iris, stay behind me. - Dad.
他要杀你  先干掉我再说
He gets to you through my dead body.
-哈里  沃利  -在
- Harry, Wally. - Yeah.
我来对付他
I got him.
天啊
Oh, God.
原来是真的
It's really true.
的确如此
Yes, it is.
再拿枪指着我  我就杀了你
Aim that gun at me and I'll kill you.
听我说
Listen to me.
你也曾是我的儿子
You were my son once.
不管我做了什么让你如此记恨
Whatever I did to make you feel this way...
我道歉
I'm sorry.
求你了  巴里
Please, Barry.
不  这不是我的名字
No. That's not my name.
-巴里  -这不是我的名字
- Barry. - That's not my name!
求你了  住手  好吗
Please! Stop, okay?
我跟你走  请不要杀死他们
I will go with you, just please, do not kill them.
我现在不会杀了他们
I'm not gonna kill them now.
他们...
They...
需要先看着你死
need to watch you die first.
-宝贝  不要  -爸  没事的
- Baby, no. - Dad, it's okay.
听着  乔
Oh, look, Joe.
她接受了自己的命运
She's accepted her fate.
你也应该如此
You should too.
-他带走了她  -他...
- He took her. - He...
爱瑞丝·韦斯特死前53分钟
-抱歉  巴里  -没事
- I'm sorry, Barry. - It's okay.
不  有事  有事  巴里
No, it's not. It's not okay, Barry.
我应该救她的  我本应该
I should have been there for her, I should...
-保护她的  -你尽力了  好吗
- have protected her. - Look, you did everything you could, all right?
你相信我  我却辜负了你
You trusted me, and I let you down.
听我说  听我说
Listen to me. Listen to me!
你无论如何都不会辜负我
There's no way you could ever let me down.
你已经成为了我心目中的英雄
You've become the hero I always knew you could be.
我会救回我们爱的女孩  行吗
I'm gonna go get our girl back, all right?
-BA  我很抱歉  -没事
- B.A., I'm so sorry. - It's okay.
我搞砸了  我很抱歉
I screwed up. I'm so sorry.
现在怎么办
So, what now?
我们现在去因凡蒂诺街
Now we go to Infantino Street.
我们清楚知道萨维塔会在何时去何地
We know exactly where Savitar's gonna be and when.
火箭筒好了吗
Is the bazooka ready?
我已经将能量源装载到设备中
I've loaded the power source into the device,
应该能提供足量的能量
which should deliver the necessary amount
将萨维塔困在神速力中
of energy to trap Savitar in the Speed Force.
我们会随时待命以防失败
We'll be on standby in case it fails.
不会失败的  不会失败的  都准备好了
It won't fail. It won't fail. It's ready.
你上次没有那东西
You didn't have that the last time,
我们现在占上风
so we have the upper hand now.
行
All right.
你们想好你们的计划
You guys figure out what your plan is.
我不能知道任何信息
I can't be here to know any of it.
你们知道我会去哪儿
You know where I'll be.
护手  好了
Gauntlets, check.
护目镜  好了
Goggles, check.
超能力  好了
Super powers? Check.
准备完毕
Locked and loaded.
别有压力
Don't stress.
特蕾西的火箭筒
Tracy's bazooka-- -
-会有用的  -特蕾西的火箭筒
- It's gonna work. - Tracy's bazooka?
-你帮了她  -我没...
- Yeah, you helped. - I didn't--
-我没帮她  -你帮了
- I didn't help. - Yes, you did.
-你激励了她  -我没激励她
- You inspired her. - I didn't inspire her.
我没做任何激励的事
I--I didn't do anything inspiring.
你知道什么是激励吗  巴里
You know what's inspiring? Barry.
英雄中的英雄  你们都是英雄
A hero among heroes. You're all heroes.
你们已经给了我
And you've all given me so,
太多太多
so much, you know?
你们给了我家  给了我目标
You've given me a home, you've given me a purpose.
现在把我引向了我喜欢的女人
Now you've led me to the woman that I adore,
我想和她过下半辈子
that I wanna spend my future with,
从始自终  但我做了什么
and through it all, what have I done?
我做了什么  我有什么贡献
What have I done? What have I contributed except--
只不过打鼓还凑合
some fair-to-middling drumming,
还把萨维塔直接引向了爱瑞丝
and lead Savitar directly to Iris.
-这话不对  -不对
- That's not fair. - It's not fair?
你话不可以这么说
It's not fair for you to say.
萨维塔骗了我们
Savitar tricked us.
我们  是我
Us? Me.
我才是张大嘴泄密的人
I'm the one who opened his big, fat mouth,
现在我们都有麻烦了  尤其是爱瑞丝
and now we're all in trouble, and especially Iris,
因为我这大嘴巴
'cause I couldn't keep my mouth shut!
可能是我泄密  好吗
Hey! That coulda happened to me, okay?
放松  真的  我也可能泄密
Easy. I mean it. That coulda happened to me,
我们都有可能
that could happen to any of us.
HR
H.R...
-你要坚守阵地  -没错
- You gonna hold down the fort? - Yeah.
当然了
Of course you are.
因为这是你的职责
'cause that's what you do.
你展示出来了
You show up.
你准备好了
You're ready.
在我们最需要你时很靠谱
Dependable when we need you the most.
听懂了吗
You hear me?
听懂了
I hear you.
行
All right.
再见
Till next time.
西斯科
Oh, Cisco.
我们该谈谈了
Time for a little chat.
西斯科
Cisco?
-我刚震波了  -什么  你看到了什么
- I just had a vibe. - What? What'd you see?
冰霜杀手
Killer Frost.
我之前预见到了
I saw this coming.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
凯特林获得超能力后
Ever since Caitlin got powers,
我就震波到我们在森林里对抗
I've had vibes of us fighting in a forest.
我一直都在抵抗这个场面
This whole time I've been fighting it.
我不想面对有一天
I didn't wanna face the fact that one day,
她会如此迷失
she'd be this far gone.
那走吧
Then go now.
让她不要犯她人生中最大的错误
Keep her from making the biggest mistake of her life.
那你呢  你会需要我的帮助
What about you? You're gonna need my help.
萨维塔现在不会和她一起
Savitar won't be with her right now.
这是我们帮她的最好机会
This is our best chance to help her.
去拯救凯特琳  我会救爱瑞丝
Go save Caitlin. I'll save Iris.
因凡蒂诺街
据另一条法律新闻
In other legal news,
杰拉德·莫里罗
the highly publicized trial
即"掠夺"  备受瞩目的审讯已经结束
of Jared Morillo, AKA Plunder, comes to a close.
今年初  莫里罗
Morillo was found guilty of grand theft
在抢劫中城博物馆时被闪电小子抓获
and aggravated assault after he was caught by Kid Flash
他因重大盗窃和故意伤害被判有罪
robbing the Central City Museum earlier this year.
请不要失败  请不要失败
Please don't fail, please don't fail.
各位
Everybody,
保持警惕
stay on alert.
准备好了
Here we go.
我知道你在这儿
I know you're here!
有种就出来见我
Come out and face me like a woman.
我没想到你真会出现
I didn't think you'd actually show.
那是因为你根本不了解我
That's 'cause you don't know anything about me.
而且也不了解凯特琳
Or Caitlin, for that matter.
萨维塔说得对
Savitar's right.
为了以神的身份与他同行
In order to join him as a god,
我得矫正凯特琳的一面
I have to cure myself of Caitlin.
必须如此
This has to happen.
我不想跟你打
I don't wanna fight you.
我也不想跟你打
I don't wanna fight you, either.
我想杀了你
I wanna kill you.
闪电侠  是时候了
Flash. This is it.
此刻取决于我们
Now the moment is upon us.
我要飞升成神
My ascension to become a god.
-今晚不行  -向我证明你是英雄
- Not tonight. - Show me you're the hero.
看看会发生什么
Let's see what happens.
我会阻止你
I'm gonna stop you.
有用了
It's working.
什么
What?
没有用
It didn't work.
为什么没用
Why didn't it work?
我被那样困住了很久很久
I spent an eternity in a trap just like that.
你以为我不知道如何防止这种情况
You think I didn't know how to prevent it
再次发生
from happening again?
魔法石
The philosopher's stone.
它由钙化的神速力能量构成
It's made of calcified Speed Force energy,
而你把它给我了
and you gave it to me.
不  各位  各位
No... guys... guys!
我失败了
I failed.
乔
Joe!
你把我困在神速力里  仿佛永恒的地狱
You stuck me with Speed Force for an eternity of hell.
欢迎来到你的地狱
Now, welcome to yours.
不  别这么做
No. Don't do this.
别这么做
Don't do this!
我终于可以摆脱你了
Now, finally, I am free of you.
巴里
Barry.
我求求你
I'm begging you, just--
-巴里  -你输了  巴里
- Barry! - You lose, Barry.
不
No!
巴里
Hi, Barry. Um...
我有些话想对你说
there's something that I need to say to you.
我爱你
I love you.
如果发生不测
And if something happens,
你得听我说这段话
I need you to hear this.
我  爱瑞丝·安·韦斯特
I, Iris Ann West,
愿意嫁给巴塞洛缪·亨利·艾伦
take you, Bartholomew Henry Allen,
作为我合法的丈夫
to be my lawfully wedded husband.
从今往后  执子之手  守护彼此
To have and to hold, from this day forward.
无论疾病还是健康
In sickness and in health.
相爱珍惜
To love and cherish,
至死不渝
untill death do us apart.